Contact

956-279-6332 (Work) jallua@hidalgocountyems.org

www.linkedin.com/in/jonathanallua-a472029a (LinkedIn) www.bcctpc.org (Company) www.hidalgocountyems.org (Company)

Top Skills

Hospitals

ACLS

Healthcare Management

Certifications

Critical Care Registered Nurse (CCRN)

Certified Flight Registered Nurse (CFRN)

Certified Flight Paramedic (FP-C)

Certified Critical Care Paramedic (CCP-C)

Certified Emergency Nurse (CEN)

Jonathan Allua

Healthcare Leader, Nurse, Paramedic, Entrepreneur San Antonio, Texas Area

Summary

Experienced administrator with a demonstrated history of working in the prehospital, hospital & healthcare industry. Skilled in Critical Care, Emergency Medicine, Critical Care Transport, and Pre-Hospital Medicine. Strong business development professional with a Bachelor's Degree in Health Sciences focused in Clinical Management & Leadership from The George Washington University School of Medicine and Health Sciences.

Experience

Hidalgo County EMS/AirMed South Texas Chief Operating Officer/Chief Flight Nurse September 2019 - Present (11 months) Edinburg, Texas

Baptist Health System
Registered Nurse
April 2019 - Present (1 year 4 months)
San Antonio, Texas

International Board of Specialty Certification (formerly BCCTPC) Vice Chairman Board of Directors July 2002 - Present (18 years 1 month)

Phi Air Medical 4 years 6 months

Manager of Business Operations September 2016 - September 2019 (3 years 1 month) San Antonio, Texas

Air Medical Base Supervisor
April 2015 - September 2016 (1 year 6 months)
Texas

CHRISTUS Trinity Mother Frances Health System Base Manager/Flight Nurse November 2013 - May 2015 (1 year 7 months) Tyler, Texas

San Antonio AirLife
Assistant Director of Clinical Operations/Flight Nurse
June 2010 - October 2013 (3 years 5 months)
San Antonio, Texas

Nash General Hospital
Registered Nurse Emergency Department
May 2009 - December 2011 (2 years 8 months)
Rocky Mount, North Carolina

Vidant Medical Center
Regional Manager/Flight Nurse/Neonatal Transport Nurse - EastCare
April 2008 - September 2009 (1 year 6 months)
Greenville, North Carolina

MedStar Washington Hospital Center Flight Paramedic October 2005 - April 2008 (2 years 7 months) Washington, District Of Columbia

Scott & White Hospital
Flight Paramedic - STAT Air
September 2004 - September 2005 (1 year 1 month)
Temple, Texas

Austin-Travis County EMS
Rescue Training Officer/Paramedic
June 2000 - December 2004 (4 years 7 months)
Austin, Texas

Education

The George Washington University School of Medicine and Health Sciences

Bachelor's Degree in Health Sciences, Clinical Management & Leadership · (2005 - 2007)

Excelsior College
Associate's Degree, Nursing · (2005 - 2007)